hi everybody welcome back to the channel
today we're going to remake Ben and
Jerry's dirt cake topped ice cream if
you like this flavor stick around and
we're going to do a whole thing
including the chocolate top so let's
[Music]
go dirt cake topped dirt cake isn't the
thing where I come from no I had to even
Google what it was um so if you don't
know dirt cake is Wikipedia describes
dirt cake as dirt and worms dirt cake is
an American cake made from sandwich
cookies and vanilla pudding in
combination with other ingredients to
create a dessert that has the
resemblance of soil or Earth it is made
by combining crushed Oreo cookies on top
of vanilla or chocolate pudding and
adding gummy worms on top
so actually looks quite nice I'd eat it
100% I've not been able to find this
flavor here uh certainly couldn't get it
back in the UK maybe we're going to go
down to the US next year do a little
drive by test out some donuts and ice
cream shops and I will try and get it
there but we can see what it is it's
vanilla pudding ice cream chocolate
sandwich cookies so that's pieces of
chocolate sandwich cookies chocolate
cookie swirls the whole thing's topped
with a milk chocolatey ganache and
chocolate cookie
crumb that sound easy enough let's break
it down item one is the vanilla pudding
ice cream so for that we're going to go
straight to the store and get some
Jello-O vanilla pudding mix nice and
easy Oreo cookies that's pretty
straightforward the cookie swirl
depending on which Ben and& jer's you
buy you can or can't find it in their
ice creams the cookie swirl just it's so
thin you can't really see it so it's
really difficult to understand what it
is really
it's it's one of two things it's either
a liquid cookie concoction almost like a
sauce with cookie crumb in it
or it's just dry cookie
pieces I don't know for this one we're
going to go with you know like a dry
cookie crumb swell and the chocolatey
top but we're going to use actual
chocolate and not chocy
so what are we going to need for this
ice cream for Ben and Jerry's dirt cake
tops you are going to need 370 G of milk
I use 2% milk 370 G of cream I use 33%
whipping cream 26 g of sugar 90 G of
invert sugar 10 G of vanilla extract 56
G of skin milk powder 84 G of Jello-O
vanilla pudding mix and the add-ins
we're just going to use straight plain
Oreos for the cookie swirl we're going
to use crushed up Oreo pieces no filling
for that for the top we're going to
use crushed Oreo again and the chocolate
on top we're going to use coca berry
milk chocolate which is about I think
45% Coco solids this recipe has 13% fat
177% sugar ice cream base only 10.9 milk
solids nonfat 41.5 solids and
58.3% of this ice cream is water okay so
let's get the stuff and do the thing and
make Ben and& Jerry's dirt cake topped
and in here I've got corn syrup the
remaining normal Su crows are skim milk
powder and finally our
vanilla pudding so put all your
ingredients in a pan and get it nicely
combined and whisked bring the
temperature up to 80 Centigrade which is
this in Fahrenheit and then take it off
the heat put it in a container and put
it in the fridge so the next stage for
this dirt cake is the Oreo cookies so
we're going to take an entire pack this
is a 270 g pack of traditional or
original Oreos we're going to take nine
cookies and put those aside and the rest
we're just going to roughly chop up and
put them in a container we're going to
use those later for those other nine
we're going to separate them and take
the cream out because we're not going to
be using it for the other part of this
recipe and then we're going to get our
pesel and water out and crumb this up
doesn't have to be perfectly powdered
but nice open crumb as you can see and
we're going to put that in another
another container and store that until
later so once your ice cream base is
completely chilled down take it out of
the fridge and with your ice cream
machine pre-chilled so I pre-chill mine
for about 5 to 10 minutes but just you
know 10 minutes is fine for most
machines put your base in there get it
churning get your cookie pieces ready
and your cookie crumb cuz a couple of
minutes before the end what we're going
to do is take the lid off add in some of
our big cookie chunks and just let that
combine in with your ice cream then
we're going to start loading up the tubs
so take one good scoop of ice cream put
it in your tub and then on top of that
put a layer of your cookie powder and
you're going to keep doing that until
all the ice cream's gone but you do need
to keep back some of that cookie powder
for the top leave about 10 mm 1 cm you
know just shy a half an inch of the top
of your ice cream tubs cuz we need to
put the chocolate on the top after the
ice cream is Frozen a little bit in the
[Music]
freezer so our ice cream has been in the
freezer for about 3 hours now we're
going to take it out as you can see tops
are nice and smooth we're going to get
our chocolate this is actually 41% Cacao
from cout Barry and we're going to add
in approximately 100 G of the chocolate
into a little container and we're going
to put in there 10 G of coconut oil this
is deodorized coconut oil so it has no
taste of coconut whatsoever you can use
a different oil if you want to I
actually quite like using extra virgin
olive oil adds a nice little flavor
change pop it in the microwave and melt
them down this should take no more than
about 30
seconds give it a nice stir make sure
all the lumps of chocolate have
completely melted and everything's
completely emulsified and then you're
just just going to gently pour this over
the top of your ice
cream and then finally top it off with
some of the powdered cookie crumb pieces
that were left from earlier once you've
done that pop it in the freezer to
completely harden
[Music]
off it's been a while since I've made a
Ben and& Jerry's combo ice cream like
this
and I don't know why cuz I love doing
these are they complicated actually this
one isn't too bad because you're just
really adding Oreos and some chocolate
but there are a few steps to it you know
I can smell the vanilla pudding let's
see what this tastes like loads of
addins love
it first thing the flavor of that
vanilla pudding comes flooding through
which is exactly what you want this is
distinctly vanilla pudding ice cream
loads of cookie
pieces and that powdered Cookie Swirl
throughout breaks up the texture of that
ice cream nicely the chocolate on top
nice and thick you can once you break
through it on the top you can actually
have some real sizable chunks of
chocolate in your ice cream too so this
is
delicious definitely going to make this
one again the van the vanilla pudding
ice cream has got kind of like a chew to
it
because they use starch to thicken you
know powdered based pudding products um
so you'll get that kind of chewy texture
to it really really good really
nice for a complex ice cream make it's
actually not too difficult with just you
know vanilla pudding powder added to the
ice cream and Oreos with a bit of
chocolate melted on top nice and easy to
give it a try do give this a try I'm
going to do another H andaz remake in a
simplified way because a lot of people
keep asking me about other ways to make
hundar Belgian chocolate so that's what
I've done I'm going to sit down in a
second and film that one so thanks very
much for watching don't forget to like
And subscribe and I'll see you next
[Music]
week